A Guide to the Virginia Marine Resources Commission Oyster Chart Collection, 1894-1977
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Marine Resources Commission Oyster Chart Collection 1894-1977
The Library of Virginia
53375
8 boxes, 1 volume and 1 chart
Virginia Marine Resources Commission
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia from the Virginia Marine Resources Commission.
Historical Information
Established in 1875 as the Virginia Fish Commission, the Virginia Marine Resources Commission (VMRC) is one of the oldest agencies in Virginia State Government. Until the last decade, shellfish regulation has dominated much of the agency's activities because of the economic and cultural importance of the oyster industry. Private leasing of State bottom for the planting and propagation of oysters appears to have begun before 1875, but it was not until 1884 that the Commonwealth set up the Board of the Chesapeake to handle the regulations of the oyster industry. Public oyster grounds were mapped (the so-called Baylor Survey) during 1892-1895.
The Fish Commission, which at that time dealt with both fresh and saltwater fisheries issues, was consolidated with the Board of the Chesapeake in 1898 to form the Board of Fisheries, later the Commission of Fisheries, which was given the task of managing all shellfish and finfish issues statewide.
The Habitat Management Division of the Commission traces its origin to 1962 when the responsibility for permit encroachments in or over State-owned submerged lands was transferred from the Office of the Attorney General to the Commission of Fisheries. This made marine management in Virginia unique in that living resources, and the habitat on which they depend, came under the jurisdiction of the same agency.
A legislative study commission in 1967 recommended a broadened mission resulting in the agency being renamed the Virginia Marine Resources Commission in 1968 by an act of the Virginia General Assembly. The Virginia Wetlands Act was passed in 1972 and placed under the management of VMRC, as was the 1980 Coastal Primary Sand Dune Protection Act. In 1982, the General Assembly broadened the 1972 Wetlands Act to include non-vegetated wetlands. In 1984, a distinct Fisheries Management Division was created and its authority over fisheries issues was strengthened. The Virginia Marine Resources Commission is headquartered in Tidewater, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Virginia Marine Resource Commission Oyster Chart collection is comprised of 100 oyster charts, 1 fish stake chart and 1 volume of oyster charts for Maryland's oyster grounds. At the time that many of these charts were created, pre-1950, the oyster grounds were known by several names: oyster rocks, oyster shoals and oyster bars. Public rocks are those set apart by the Baylor Survey of 1894 for the exclusive use of the public. The other areas were classified as lying outside of the Baylor Survey and were eligible for leasing by private individuals. Public rocks were used by individual tongers who paid an annual license fee; tongers removed oysters from the public beds with a hand tong. The private or leased grounds were rented from the state and the oysters were removed by dredges.
Fred E. Reudiger (1863-1956) supervised the survey or resurvey for many of Virginia's public oyster grounds that are in Tidewater Virginia. Prior to his employment with the Virginia State Commission of Fisheries, he was a surveyor for Accomac County. The surveys can include the names of oyster planting grounds, the acreage of rented oyster grounds and their lessees. Numerous place names are present, as are station names, lighthouses and their locations, and the location of low water lines and marshes. The coordinates have been recorded for the area charted, when possible.
Arrangement
Arranged geographically and then by date.
Contents List
- [Aerial photograph of Chuckatuck Creek]. Scale 1:12,000. 15 July 1977. Time 10:05 AM. (W 76°30'49"/N 36°54'18"; W 76°31'08"/N 36°54'51"; W 76°30'05"/N 36°55'15"; W 76°29'45"/N 36°54'42"; W 76°30'49"/N 36°54'18"),1977. (Box 1)
- [Aerial photograph of Smith Island and Cherry Island]. Scale not given. 18 November 1977. (W 76°03'15"--W 76°01'07"/N 38°00'08"--N 37°56'53"),1977. (Box 1)
- [Aerial photograph of Janes Island, Cedar Island, Pocomoke Sound Wildlife Management Area and Saxis Marsh Waterfowl Management Area and Refuge]. Scale not given. (W 75°54'48"--W 75°38'14"/N 38°01'52"--N 37°53'43"),No Date. (Box 1)
- [Aerial photograph of Smith Island and Janes Island and Cherry Island]. Scale not given. (W 76°03'10"--W 75°51'33"/N 38°02'41"--N 37°52'52"),No Date. (Box 1)
- [Aerial photograph of Smith Island]. Scale not given. (W 76°03'22"--W 75°58'34"/N 38°02'36"--N 37°55'11"). ,No Date. (Box 1)
- Maryland Shellfish Commission. Chart No. 5 Natural Oyster Bars Somerset County and Adjacent Waters. Scale 1:20,000. 32.5 x 44 inches. (W 76°01'49"--W 75°49'24"/N 38°16'06"--N 38°09'54"),No Date. (Box 1)
- Maryland Shellfish Commission. Chart No. 6 Natural Oyster Bars Somerset County and Adjacent Waters Maryland. Scale 1:20,000. 32.5 x 44 inches. (W 76°08'11"--W 76°01'52"/N 38°08'29"--N 38°05'25"),No Date. (Box 1)
- Maryland Shellfish Commission. Chart No. 7 Natural Oyster Bars Somerset County and Adjacent Waterways Maryland. Scale 1:20,000. 32.75 x 44 inches. (W 76°00'53"--W 75°47'28"/N 38°08'06"--N 38°01'58"),No Date. (Box 1)
- Edward B. Mathews, State Geologist of Maryland and Wilber A. Nelson, State Geologist of Virginia. The Maryland -Virginia Boundary Determined by the Award of Arbitrators, 1877. Sheet Two. Scale 1:40,000. 61.5 x 90.5 cm,1927. (Box 1)
- Edward B. Mathews, State Geologist of Maryland and Wilber A. Nelson, State Geologist of Virginia. The Maryland-Virginia Boundary Determined by the Award of Arbitrators, 1877. Sheet Three. Scale 1:40,000. 61 x 92 cm,1927. (Box 1)
- J.B. Sinclair, Jr., C.E. Map 103 Sheet 3 Oyster Planting Grounds in Back River 1922. Scale 1:6000. 35 x 49 inches. (W 76°20'57"/N 37°02'39"; W 76°22'15"/N 37°03'10"; W 76°20'38"/N 37°05'46"; W 76°19'19"/N 37°05'15"; W 76°20'57"/N 37°02'39"),1922. (Box 2)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Public Oyster Grounds James River. 1930s. Scale Bar in Statute Miles. 22 x 51 inches. Printed map. (W 76°30'41"/N 36°53'12"; W 76°43'48"/N 37°06'50"; W 76°36'13"/N 37°10'34"; W 76°24'13"/N 36°57'54"; W 76°30'41"/N 36°53'12"),1930s. (Box 2)
- Oyster Producing Section of James River, VA. 28 March 1932. Scale: statue of miles. 14 x 29 inches. Printed map. (W 76°27'31"/N 36°52'06"; W 76°43'40"/N 37°05'32"; W 76°37'36"/N 37°08'47"; W 76°36'17"/N 37°09'44"; W 76°22'03"/N 36°58'06"; W 76°27'31"/N 36°52'06"),1932. (Box 2)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Oyster Planting Grounds in Southwest Branch Back River Elisabeth County, Virginia. 20 March 1934. Scale 1:6,000. 19.5 x 41.5 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°20'54"/N 37°02'34"; W 76°22'35"/N 37°03'11"; W 76°20'58"/N 37°06'03"; W 76°19'17"/N 37°05'26"; W 76°20'54"/N 37°02'34"),1934. (Box 2)
- Fred. E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Warwick River, Warwick County, Virginia 1937. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 54 inches. Printed map. (W 76°32'52"/N 37°04'43"; W 76°34'09"/N 37°06'21"; W 76°33'27"/N 37°06'41"; W 76°32'11"/N 37°05'04"; W 76°32'52"/N 37°04'43"),1937. (Box 2)
- S.W. Armistead, C.E. Survey of Property Sold by E.C. Hathaway and Wife and Chas. H. Consolvo and Wife to George W. Syer by Deed dated Jan. 1, 1938. Scale 1:1,800. 25 x 54 inches. Blue-line print. (W 76°05'34"--W 76°02'26"/N 36°54'33"--N 36°53'34"),1938. (Box 2)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds James River Map NO 4. Warwick County, Virginia. 1938. Scale 1:10,000. 31.5 x 53.5 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°33'12"/N 37°04'15"; W 76°37'39"/N 37°07'34"; W 76°37'25"/N 37°07'48"; W 76°33'26"/N 37°04'36"; W 76°32'53"/N 37°04'49"; W 76°34'15"/N 37°06'34"; W 76°33'57"/N 37°06'44"; W 76°34'16"/N 37°07'11"; W 76°34'00"/N 37°07'15"; W 76°32'01"/N 37°04'53"; W 76°31'29"/N 37°04'51"; W 76°33'12"/N 37°04'15"),1938. (Box 2)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds James River Map No. 4 Warwick County Virginia. 1938. Scale 1:10,000. 27 x 49 inches. Printed map. (W 76°34'06"/N 37°02'32"; W 76°37'41"/N 37°07'39"; W 76°34'50"/N 37°08'28"; W 76°31'09"/N 37°03'50"; W 76°34'06"/N 37°02'32"),1938. (Box 2)
- U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey and Virginia Department of Marine Resources. United States - East Coast Chesapeake By -Virginia James River to Jamestown Island. 11th edition. December 1961. Scale 1:40,000 at Lat. 37°03'. 44 x 36 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°28'00"/N 36°51'00"; W 76°50'00"/N 37°10'00"; W 76°42'00"/N 37°16'00"; W 76°20'00"/N 36°57'00"; W 76°28'00"/N 36°51'00"),1961. (Box 2)
- Charles Kerns, and Geo. H. Badger, Jr. Engineer. Map No. 254 Oyster Planting Grounds James River City of Newport News Virginia, 1962. Scale 1:10,000. 38 x 59 inches. Printed map. (W 76°29'43"/N 36°56'43"; W 76°35'24"/N 37°02'22"; W 76°31'39"/N 37°04'33"; W 76°25'05"/N 36°59'32"; W 76°29'43"/N 36°56'43"),1962. (Box 2)
- Geo. H. Badger, Jr., drawn by J.K. Sinclair. Oyster Planting Grounds James River Map No. 4 City of Newport News Virginia. 1962. Scale 1:10,000. 30 x 58 inches. Printed map. (W 76°34'28"/N 37°03'21"; W 76°37'57"/N 37°07'41"; W 76°34'50"/N 37°08'34"; W 76°31'11"/N 37°04'40"; W 76°34'28"/N 37°03'21"),1962. (Box 2)
- Parsons, Brinckerhoff, Hail and MacDonald. Commonwealth of Virginia Department of Highways Hampton Roads Project Oyster Bed Locations. 18 June 1954. Scale not given. 22 x 36 inches. Diazotype print. (W 76°18'27"--W 76°17'51"/N 36°59'18"--N 36°58'48"),1954. (Box 2)
- Parsons, Brinckerhoff, Hall and MacDonald Engineers. Commonwealth of Virginia Department of Highways Hampton Roads Project Relocation of Hampton Creek Channel. 1 September 1954. Scale varies. 22 x 36 inches. Diazotype print. (W 76°20'49"--W 76°19'18"/N 37°00'58"--N 36°59'45"),1954. (Box 2)
- Parsons, Brinckerhoff, Hall and MacDonald Engineers. Commonwealth of Virginia Department of Highways Hampton Roads Project Site Conditions. 1 September 1954. Scale 1:1000. 22 x36 inches. Diazotype print. (W 76°21'24"--W 76°15'06"/N 37°01'43"--N 36°56'47"),1954. (Box 2)
- Geo. H. Badger, Jr., Drawn by Virginia E. Jones. Back River, City of Hampton Virginia 1967. Revised May 1971. Scale 1:10,000. 32 x 65 inches. Printed chart with manuscript notations. (W 76°21'40"/N 37°02'38"; W 76°23'14"/N 37°06'47"; W 76°17'15"/N 37°08'14"; W 76°15'40"/N 37°04'04"; W 76°21'40"/N 37°02'38"),1971. (Box 2)
- [Manuscript Chart of Chesapeake Bay and York River showing parcels along Peninsula side from just east of Messick Point to West of Lawnes Creek]. 1900. Scale not given. Ca. 35.5 x 75 inches. Manuscript map. (W 76°17'25"/N 37°06'14"; W 76°23'00"/N 37°10'56"; W 76°17'20"/N 37°15'13"; W 76°11'45"/N 37°10'32"; W 76°17'25"/N 37°06'14"). Fragile,1900. (Box 3)
- W.F. O'Hart Diplomated Surveyor for Virginia. Plan of Oyster Planting Grounds in the Corrotoman River and Its Tributaries Lancaster County State of Virginia. January 1924. Scale 1:7,200. 31 x 61 inches. Facsimile, mylar copy. (W 76°30'58"--W 76°24'43"/N 37°44'08"--N 37°38'19"),1924. (Box 3)
- W.F. O'Hara, Diplomated Surveyor for Virginia. Plan of Oyster Planting Grounds in the Corrotoman River and Its Tributaries Lancaster county State of Virginia. January 1924. Scale 1:7,200. 32 x 61 inches. Blue print. (W 76°29'48"--W 76°26'36"/N 37°42'51"--N 37°38'38"),1924. (Box 3)
- F.M. Murphy, Surveyor for Commission of Fisheries. Yeocomico River Private and Public Oyster Grounds State of Virginia 1927. Scale 1:10,800. 33 x 27 inches. Facsimile, mylar copy. (W 76°35'17"--W 76°30'53"/N 38°03'09"--N 37°58'54"),1927. (Box 3)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Willoughby Area Hampton Roads Virginia 1937. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 53 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°15'57"/N 36°55'23"; W 76°20'36"/N 36°58'39"; W 76°18'42"/N 37°00'23"; W 76°14'03"/N 36°57'06"; W 76°15'57"/N 36°55'23"),1937. (Box 3)
- Fred E. Reudiger. No. 220 Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds York River Virginia. 31 January 1930. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 52 inches. Manuscript. (W 76°23'08"/N 37°12'57"; W 76°30'28"/N 37°13'14"; W 76°30'17"/N 37°16'03"; W 76°22'58"/N 37°15'45"; W 76°23'08"/N 37°12'57"),1930. (Box 4)
- Fred E. Reudiger. York River, Virginia Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Green Point to Ferry Point. 1932. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 55 inches. Drafting paper. (W 76°35'39"/N 37°16'20"; W 76°41'17"/N 37°22'54"; W 76°38'21"/N 37°24'29"; W 76°32'43"/N 37°17'56"; W 76°35'39"/N 37°16'20"),1932. (Box 4)
- Fred E. Ruediger. York River, Virginia Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Poropotank Creek to West Point. 1932. Scale 1:10,000. Drafting paper. (W 76°44'18"/N 37°25'32"; W 76°48'29"/N 37°30'09"; W 76°46'13"/N 37°31'26"; W 76°42'02"/N 37°26'49"; W 76°44'18"/N 37°25'32"),1932. (Box 4)
- Fred E. Reudiger, Engineer. York River, Virginia Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Claybank to Richardson 1932. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 55 inches. Manuscript. (W 76°36'53"/N 37°18'16"; W 76°43'25"/N 37°25'01"; W 76°41'18"/N 37°26'18"; W 76°34'47"/N 37°19'34"; W 76°36'53"/N 37°18'16"),1932. (Box 4)
- Fred. E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Poquoson York County Virginia 1935. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 50 inches. Manuscript. (W 76°22'39"/N 37°06'53"; W 76°27'21"/N 37°08'55"; W 76°24'43"/N 37°12'47"; W 76°20'01"/N 37°10'44"; W 76°22'39"/N 37°06'53"),1935. (Box 4)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Floyds Bay York County Virginia. 1938. Bar Scale in feet. 22 x 31 inches. Drafting paper. (W 76°22'27"/N 37°08'02"; W 76°22'41"/N 37°08'15"; W 76°22'12"/N 37°08'34"; W 76°21'58"/N 37°08'21"; W 76°22'27"/N 37°08'02"),1938. (Box 4)
- [Public Oyster Grounds Elizabeth River]. Ca. 1930s. Scale not given. 42 x 27 inches. Diazotype print. (W 76°23'50"--W 76°16'03"/N 36°57'54"--N 36°45'17"),Ca. 1930s. (Box 4)
- Geo. H. Badger, Jr.. Map No. 247-63 Oyster Planting Grounds Poquoson York County, Virginia. 1963. Scale 1:10,000. 33 x 55 inches. Manuscript. (W 76°22'39"/N 37°06'53"; W 76°27'21"/N 37°08'55"; W 76°24'43"/N 37°12'47"; W 76°20'01"/N 37°10'44"; W 76°22'39"/N 37°06'53"),1963. (Box 4)
- J.K. Sinclair. York River District 15 York County Oyster Planting Ground Leases. Revised Drawing 10 November 1969. Scale 1:10,000. 24 x 50 inches. Manuscript. (W 76°35'23"/N 37°16'17"; W 76°40'49"/N 37°22'24"; W 76°38'11"/N 37°23'53"; W 76°32'45"/N 37°17'46"; W 76°35'23"/N 37°16'17"),1969. (Box 4)
- York River, Virginia Poropotank Creek to West Point. Revised Feb. 1970. Scale 1:10,000. Printed chart. (W 76°44'14"/N 37°24'59"; W 76°49'19"/N 37°31'00"; W 76°46'43"/N 37°32'23"; W 76°41'38"/N 37°26'21"; W 76°44'14"/N 37°24'59"),1970. (Box 4)
- J.K. Sinclair. Map of Oyster Planting Grounds in Lloyds Bay York County, Va. Revised June 1975. 22 x 31 inches. Manuscript. (W 76°21'19"/N 37°08'59"; W 76°21'51"/N 37°09'39"; W 76°21'25"/N 37°09'52"; W 76°20'53"/N 37°09'13"; W 76°21'19"/N 37°08'59"),1975. (Box 4)
- P.C. Warwick, Jr. Isle of Wight Co. Chart No. 1 Oyster Planting Grounds, State of Virginia, 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 47.75 x 24 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°40'17"/N 37°02'58"; W 76°40'29"/N 37°07'25"; W 76°38'49"/N 37°07'28"; W 76°38'38"/N 37°03'01"; W 76°40'17"/N 37°02'58"),1901. (Box 5)
- R.E..L. Simmons and P.C. Warwick, Jr. Isle of Wight Co. Chart No. 4 Oyster Planting Grounds, State of Virginia, 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 36 x 35.75 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°34'36"/N 36°59'51"; W 76°34'44"/N 36°59'51"; W 76°34'45"/N 37°00'01"; W 76°35'00"/N 37°00'23"; W 76°34'51"/N 37°00'35"; W 76°34'33"/N 37°00'53"; W 76°34'34"/N 37°01'13"; W 76°34'56"/N 37°01'31"; W 76°33'06"/N 37°01'48"; W 76°32'15"/N 37°00'34"; W 76°33'25"/N 37°00'07"; W 76°33'38"/N 37°00'18"; W 76°34'13"/N 37°00'10"; W 76°34'14"/N 36°59'55"; W 76°34'36"/N 36°59'51"),1901. (Box 5)
- P.C. Warwick, Jr. Isle of Wight Co. Chart No. 5 Oyster Planting Grounds State of Virginia 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 30.75 x 20 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°36'16"/N 36°58'41"; W 76°37'29"/N 37°00'00"; W 76°34'53"/N 37°01'31"; W 76°33'40"/N 37°00'12"; W 76°36'16"/N 36°58'41"),1901. (Box 5)
- P.C. Warwick, Jr. Isle of Wight Co. Chart No. 6 Oyster Planting Grounds, State of Virginia 1901. Scale 1;5,000. 35 x 20 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°38'03"/N 36°58'10"; W 76°38'14"/N 36°59'59"; W 76°36'44"/N 37°00'04"; W 76°36'34"/N 36°58'15"; W 76°38'03"/N 36°58'10"),1901. (Box 5)
- R.E. L. Simmons and P.C. Warwick Jr. Isle of Wight Co. Chart No. 8 Oyster Planting Grounds, State of Virginia, 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 30 x 32.25 inches. Printed chart,1901. (Box 5)
- R.E. L. Simmons and P.C. Warwick Jr. Isle of Wight Co., Chart No. 9, Oyster Planting Grounds, State of Virginia, 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 22 x 46 inches. Printed chart,1901. (Box 5)
- R.E. L. Simmons and P.C. Warwick Jr. Isle of Wight Co., Chart No. 9, Oyster Planting Grounds, State of Virginia, 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 22 x 46 inches. Printed chart,1901. (Box 5)
- R.E. L. Simmons and P.C. Warwick Jr. Isle of Wight Co. Chart No. 10. Oyster Planting grounds, State of Virginia, 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 32.75 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°29'41"/N 36°55'28"; W 76°29'49"/N 36°55'29"; W 76°29'57"/N 36°56'00"; W 76°29'53"/N 36°56'15"; W 76°30'15"/N 36°56'53"; W 76°29'56"/N 36°56'58"; W 76°29'50"/N 36°56'47"; W 76°29'44"/N 36°56'40"; W 76°29'46"/N 36°56'28"; W 76°29'08"/N 36°56'18"; W 76°29'02"/N 36°56'29"; W 76°29'04"/N 36°56'33"; W 76°28'55"/N 36°56'32"; W 76°29'02"/N 36°56'00"; W 76°29'41"/N 36°55'28"),1901. (Box 5)
- P.C. Warwick, Jr. Isle of Wight Co. Chart No. 11 Oyster Planting Grounds, State of Virginia, 1901. Scale 1:5,000. 34.5 x 13.5 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°31'12"/N 36°53'59"; W 76°31'43"/N 36°54'33"; W 76°29'58"/N 36°55'34"; W 76°29'27"/N 36°55'00"; W 76°31'12"/N 36°53'59"),1901. (Box 5)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds/Nansemond River, Virginia, Cedar Point-Western Branch. ca. 1935. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 55 inches. Printed chart,No Date. (Box 5)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds James River Map NO. 2 Isle of Wight County Virginia, Days Point to Coopers Point. 1938. Scale 1:10,000. 30.75 x 53 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°30'02"/N 36°57'30"; W 76°33'15"/N 36°59'57"; W 76°33'49"/N 36°59'38"; W 76°34'35"/N 36°59'59"; W 76°34'12"/N 37°00'44"; W 76°29'29"/N 36°58'01"; W 76°29'41"/N 36°57'44"; W 76°30'02"/N 36°57'30"),1938. (Box 5)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds James River Map No. 3 (256) Isle of Wight County, Virginia. 1938. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 53 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°38'28"/N 37°01'04"; W 76°41'31"/N 37°05'00"; W 76°38'40"/N 37°06'24"; W 76°35'37"/N 37°02'28"; W 76°38'28"/N 37°01'04"),1938. (Box 5)
- Geo. H. Badger, Jr. and drawn by J.K. Sinclair. Map No. 243 Oyster Planting Grounds James River Nansemond County, Virginia 1962. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 44 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°28'23"/N 36°52'56"; W 76°31'42"/N 36°56'18"; W 76°29'22"/N 36°57'31"; W 76°26'22"/N 36°54'21"; W 76°27'29"/N 36°53'34"; W 76°28'23"/N 36°52'56"),1962. (Box 5)
- Charles J. Kerns and Geo. H. Badger, Jr. Oyster Planting Grounds James River Map No. 256 Isle of Wight County Virginia. 1962. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 53 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°39'28"/N 37°01'49"; W 76°41'36"/N 37°06'50"; W 76°37'43"/N 37°08'06"; W 76°39'28"/N 37°01'49"),1962. (Box 5)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds James River Map No. 256 Isle of Wight County, Virginia. 1962. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 53 inches. Printed chart. (W 76°38'28"/N 37°01'04"; W 76°41'31"/N 37°05'00"; W 76°38'40"/N 37°06'24"; W 76°35'37"/N 37°02'28"; W 76°38'28"/N 37°01'04"),1962. (Box 5)
- Fred E. Reudiger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Severn River, Virginia Southwest Branch.Scale 1:5,000. 30 x 52 inches. Map on drafting paper. (76°27'08"/N 37°17'11"; W 76°27'45"/N 37°17'31"; W 76°26'56"/N 37°18'32"; W 76°26'18"/N 37°18'13"; W 76°27'08"/N 37°17'11",Ca. 1930s. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Reudiger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Severn River, Virginia. North West Branch. Scale in meters. Map on drafting paper. (W 76°27'51"/N 37°18'40"; W 76°29'09"/N 37°19'21"; W 76°28'34"/N 37°20'03"; W 76°27'16"/N 37°19'22"; W 76°27'51"/N 37°18'40"),ca. 1930s. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Severn River, Virginia, Northwest Branch. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 40 inches. (W 76°28'34"--W 76°26'04"/N 37°20'06"--N 37°18'46"),1930s. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds, Ware River, Virginia, Bailey's Wharf to Pig Hill. Scale 1:5,000. 20.5 x 43.25 inches. (W 76°27'42"/N 37°22'59"; W 76°29'40"/N 37°24'12"; W 76°29'13"/N 37°24'38"; W 76°27'16"/N 37°23'25"; W 76°27'42"/N 37°22'59"),1930s. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. No. 221 Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds York River Virginia Sheet No. 2. January 31st 1930. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 55 inches. (W 76°30'26"/N 37°13'52"; W 76°38'01"/N 37°18'28"; W 76°37'36"/N 37°18'42"; W 76°35'15"/N 37°19'52"; W 76°29'05"/N 37°15'51"; W 76°30'26"/N 37°13'52"),1930. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. York River, Virginia. Resurvey of Oyster Planting Grounds Poropotank Creek to West Point.Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 55 inches. (W 76°43'24"/N 37°25'22"; W 76°48'33"/N 37°30'52"; W 76°46'42"/N 37°31'14"; W 76°41'38"/N 37°26'04"; W 76°43'24"/N 37°25'22"),1932. (Box 6)
- Fred. E. Ruediger. Piankatank River, Virginia Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Wilton Point to Freeport. Scale 1:5,000. Entire sheet, 31 x 58 inches. Printed chart,1932. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. York River, Virginia Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Green Point to Ferry Point. Scale 1:5,000. 30.75 x 54.75 inches. (W 76°34'57"/N 37°16'41"; W 76°39'42"/N 37°22'01"; W 76°37'57"/N 37°23'00"; W 76°33'11"/N 37°17'41"; W 76°34'57"/N 37°16'41"),1932. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Resurvey of Oyster Planting Grounds/Ware River, Virginia/Ware Neck Point to Bailey's Wharf (first of three stapled together). Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 51 inches. Drafting paper.(W 76°27'51"--W 76°24'31"/N 37°23'15"--N 37°22'03"),No Date. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Osyter Planting Grounds/Wormley's Creek/York County, Virginia/1935.Scale 1:2500. 31 x 37 inches.(W 76°28'24"--W 76°28'00"/N 37°12'58"--N 37°12'13"),1935. (Box 6)
- Fred. E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds/Ware River, Virginia/Ware Neck Point to Bailey's Wharf. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 52 inches. Chart on drafting paper. (W 76°24'17"/N 37°19'20"; W 76°30'18"/N 37°22'18"; W 76°28'22"/N 37°24'46"; W 76°22'21"/N 37°21'47"; W 76°24'17"/N 37°19'20"). Map no. 251 and stapled to Resurvey of Oyster Planting Grounds Wormley Creek, York County, Virginia 1935 Map no. 246,Ca. 1935. (Box 6)
- Fred E Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Wormleys Creek York County, Virginia 1935. Scale 1:2500. 31.5 x 38 inches. (W 76°28'19"--W 76°27'56"/N 37°12'57"--N 37°12'00"),1935. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-survey of Oyster Planting Grounds North River Gloucester and Mathews Counties Virginia 1936. 2nd of 3 maps stapled together. Scale 1:10,000. 32 x 53 inches. (W 76°27'07"--W 76°23'54"/N 37°27'07"--N 37°24'52"),1936. (Box 6)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Ware River, Virginia Ware Neck Point to Bailey's Wharf. Scale 1:5,000. 30.5 x 51 inches. (W 76°28'08"--W 76°24'25"/N 37°23'45"--N 37°22'00"),1936. (Box 6)
- J.K. Sinclair. Map of Oyster Planting Grounds Near Goodwins Islands District No. 15 York County, Va. Scale 1:10,000. 20.25 x 22 inches. (W 76°27'19"--W 76°24'48"/N 37°12'36"--N 37°12'01"),Revised January 1970. (Box 6)
- Geo. H. Badger, Jr. Chisman Creek York County, Virginia. 1964. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 38.25 inches. (W 76°27'24"--W 76°24'10"/N 37°11'08"--N 37°10'33"),Revised 13 May 1970. (Box 6)